<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
     xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
     xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
     xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
     xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
     xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
     >
  <channel>
    <title>happy bubble</title>
    <link>http://zombified.github.com/blog</link>
    <description>Joel Kleier's blog about anything.</description>
    <pubDate>Fri, 27 Apr 2012 03:00:27 GMT</pubDate>
    <generator>Blogofile</generator>
    <sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
    <sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
    <item>
      <title>I'm Not Dead Yet!</title>
      <link>http://zombified.github.com/blog/2012/04/26/i'm-not-dead-yet!</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Apr 2012 00:00:00 CDT</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[misc]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://zombified.github.com/blog/2012/04/26/i'm-not-dead-yet!</guid>
      <description>I'm Not Dead Yet!</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The last several months have been quite eventful for me, and this poor excuse for a blog has been low on my list of priorities -- but no longer!. Well, maybe it's moved up a notch or two.</p>
<p>I will probably continue my declare 'MelonJS' articles soon, but for now I am on to other things.</p>
<p>First up is my <a href="http://www.ludumdare.com/compo/ludum-dare-23/?action=preview&amp;uid=7263">ludum dare #23 entry</a>, a text adventure called 'The Tiny World'. It's not fancy, and it's built from scratch (I know, I know -- I probably should have just gone with inform7). Play it if you like, it's probably mediocre at best!</p>
<p>Second up, my new job is a lot about Python and, more specifically, Plone, so expect to see some posts on those things.</p>]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Updates</title>
      <link>http://zombified.github.com/blog/2012/02/24/updates</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Feb 2012 00:00:00 CST</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[misc]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://zombified.github.com/blog/2012/02/24/updates</guid>
      <description>Updates</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I Decided to sit down and design a new theme, which is still rough and in development. </p>
<p>I also decided it was time to move my website over to github. This is for a couple of reasons... so I don't have all my eggs in one basket (Google), and so I don't have to do as much maintenance.</p>
<p>Basically the appengine tools are tools that I only use for updating my website/blog. Why not replace those tools with a single tool that I use for other stuff to?</p>
<p>Now I just need to use git, which I don't have to manually update and setup since it's in my OS's package repositories! Woohoo, less work for me!</p>]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
