<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
     xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
     xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
     xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
     xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
     xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
     >
  <channel>
    <title>happy bubble</title>
    <link>http://zombified.github.com/blog</link>
    <description>Joel Kleier's blog about anything.</description>
    <pubDate>Fri, 24 Feb 2012 17:53:27 GMT</pubDate>
    <generator>Blogofile</generator>
    <sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
    <sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
    <item>
      <title>Website stuff</title>
      <link>http://zombified.github.com/blog/2011/12/07/website-stuff</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Dec 2011 00:00:00 CST</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[LD48]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[gamedev]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://zombified.github.com/blog/2011/12/07/website-stuff</guid>
      <description>Website stuff</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Spent a little time re-arranging my website. Nothing fancy, just a few tweaks. I kind of like it plain text... need to find the time to style it slightly though. The typeface is hurting my eyes a little.</p>
<p>Also updated my twitter username! 'pbdiode'. Figured I'd stick with it since that's what I'm registered at <a href="http://ludumdare.com">ld48</a> with. It's time for a change I think.</p>]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>We Have Sound</title>
      <link>http://zombified.github.com/blog/2011/12/06/we-have-sound</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Dec 2011 00:00:00 CST</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[LD48]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[gamedev]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://zombified.github.com/blog/2011/12/06/we-have-sound</guid>
      <description>We Have Sound</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>10 Days left until the event!</p>
<p>I will be recording the event -- I'll be using 'recordmydesktop', with the following command:</p>
<pre><code>recordmydesktop --no-sound --on-the-fly-encoding --v_quality 30 --no-frame
</code></pre>
<p>Then I just let it sit! Hopefully I'll have enough disk space... it is set to record at a crappy quality, so I should have enough space. And my tests indicate the text is at least readable... eh. We'll see.</p>
<p>Now on to finding out about audio...</p>
<p>WolframTones seems interesting, but I can't seem to get firefox configured correctly for it. I'm also having issues setting up PulseAudio, so I may have issues recording even a tone matrix output. Ugh.</p>
<p>I think I'm just going to forego the music for now. Less to stress me out, less to actually work on during the competition. I will, at least, have good sound effects from sfxr!</p>
<p>So, what do I need to do next to prepare?</p>
<ul>
<li>I know what tech I'm using -- Javascript/HTML/CSS, melonJS</li>
<li>I'm axing the music generation</li>
<li>I have my tools ready -- a terminal, tmux, vim, chromium and firefox, sfxr, gimp, recordmydesktop, tiled</li>
<li>I've posted an 'I'm In' message on the ludum dare website (http://www.ludumdare.com/compo/2011/12/06/im-in-255/) -- I posted under 'pbdiode', supposedly pronounced 'lead diode'. I think it sounded better in my head.</li>
</ul>
<p>I think it's time I practice a bit. I think I'll do some exercises to get myself more familiar with melonJS.</p>]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
